Joseph Golden Papers
Joseph Golden Papers
1957-1967
Golden, Joseph, 1928-
1.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, dramatist. Collection includes typescript drafts and revisions of books, plays, and television scripts.
149008
Biographical History
Joseph Golden was an American writer and professor in the College of Visual and Performing Arts at Syracuse University.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Joseph Golden Papers comprise two series: Miscellaneous and Writings. Miscellaneous contains a memo to Golden from a colleague at Syracuse Unviersity. Writings contains the working manuscript of Golden's book, The Death of Tinkerbell: The American Theatre in the Twentieth Century, correspondence about a speaking engagement at which he presented a paper entitled "Death of the Left in the Thirties," and typescripts of plays and television scripts which he authored.
Related Material
The Syracuse University Archives has papers relating to Golden's years at SU.
Subject and Genre Headings
Dance and theatre; Literature -- American Fiction; Popular culture; Golden, Joseph, 1928-; American drama -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Dramatists, American.; Manuscripts for publication.; Scripts (documents); Television scripts.; Authors.; Dramatists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Miscellaneous
  - Memo, 1966 (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Books
    - The Death of Tinkerbell: The American Theatre in the Twentieth Century
      - 1 vol. (TMs) (Box 1)
      - Permisions (Box 1)
      - Rough drafts
        - Chapter I, "The death of Tinkerbell (Box 1)
        - Chapter II, "O'Neill and the passing of pleasure" (Box 1)
        - Chapter III, "The loud small voice of the poet" (Box 1)
        - Chapter IV, "Heroes, non-heroes, anti-heroes" (Box 1)
        - Chapter V, "The modern medievalists" (Box 1)
        - Chapter VI, "The birth of Tinkerbell" (Box 1)
        - General (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - "Death of the Left in the Thirties", 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - "The Loud Small Voice of the Poet", 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Plays
    - The Bait at Leadball Junction, 1961 (Box 2)
    - The Butterfly that Blushed (Box 2)
    - The Contract, 1964 (Box 2)
    - The Exhibit, 1963 (Box 2)
    - A Garden Shady (Box 2)
    - How to Grow a Musical (Box 2)
    - Johnny Moonbeam and the Silver Arrow, 1957 (Box 2)
    - The Maisie Concerto, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Spinner Boy, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Rough drafts
    - Leonardo (Box 2)
  - Television scripts
    - "A Body Came to Tea", 1960 (Box 2)
    - "A Small Case of Friendship" (Box 2)
    - "The Lunch Box, 1961 (Box 2)
    - "The Rebellion of Ruby Redrock", 1960 (Box 2)
    - "River Deep", 1960 (Box 2)